Dheemanth A.N.

dheemanth.simha01@gmail.com +91 7019817873 Bengaluru, Karnataka

Summary

Young professional currently pursuing Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science. Hands-on experience in Full Stack Web Development and provided full-stack digital marketing support to budding businesses.

Responsible for **scaling up the revenue** of an E-commerce startup, recognized by Startup India by **9 times** through in-depth knowledge of **Facebook Pixel** and implementing key inferences from **analytics** to improve conversion metrics.

Keen interest in tech, entrepreneurship ,fitness, and an adventurous Biker exploring trails,offroads and unexplored marvels.

Education

Dayananda Sagar College Of Engineering [2019-2023]

B.E. Computer Science and Engineering • Bengaluru, Karnataka CGPA - 9.14 [Till Sophomore year]

Sadhana PU College

Science - PCMC • Bengaluru, Karnataka

03/2019

Pre University Topper . 97.33% in PCM .Overall 96.8%.

Prarthana Education Society

Class 10 CBSE • Bengaluru, Karnataka

03/2017

Secured 10 CGPA .Recipient of Letter of Appreciation from CBSE Board.

Technical Skills

- **Programming Languages**: C, C++, Java, Python
- Markup language : HTML
- Stylesheet Language: CSS
- Scripting Languages: Javascript
- IT Constructs: Data structures and Algorithms, OOPS, REST API
- Development constructs: NodeJS, EJS, React, Express, Bootstrap
- Development tools: Microsoft Visual Studio Code, Git, Github, Gitpod, cURL, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, Geany
- DB language: MySQL,MongoDB
- API development and Testing tools: Postman, Grafana, Thunder client, Chrome dev tools
- Project Management and Documentation: Atlassian Confluence, Jira, Github Projects

Industry Experience

Brane Enterprises [NSL HUB]

Quality Assurance Intern • Hyderabad, Telangana

09/2021 - Present

- Involved in manual testing of solutions, performed a total of 950+ tests in Smoke Suite and Regression Suite test cases.
- **Identified critical bugs** in the platform and thoroughly documented the steps to reproduce the bugs.
- Part of the **automated testing team**,created automated test scripts **in Postman** which **reduced** the overall **testing time** by **10–15 minutes**.

Web Developer and Digital Marketing Manager • Bangalore, Karnataka

- Built and deployed fully functional E-commerce Website with WordPress and Woocommerce, which went on to get recognized by Startup India and made a 6 figure revenue within 2 months.
- Ranked close to 5 products on the first page of Google's Search
 Engine Result Page in 3 months via Search Engine Optimization,
 alongside huge E-commerce giants such as Amazon, Flipkart, and
 BigBasket.
- Designed, Curated, and Automated Facebook and Instagram Ads to increase the ROI by 9 times via Facebook Pixel and conversion campaigns.

Digitalyaan

Founder and CEO • Bangalore, Karnataka

07/2019 - 05/2021

- Started a Digital Marketing agency in the freshman year of my college, onboarded 7 clients.
- Provided Digital Marketing consultation for 10 businesses.
- Formed a team of freelancers. Managed and drove a team to provide top-notch service to 7 businesses.

Projects

1) DeCrypt [Web development] View the project on Github

A customized collection of your wishlist cryptocurrencies.

This web app allows real-time and live cryptocurrency tracking in INR. The user can select his or her coins of interest and keep track of them without having to search in a stack of coins every time.

- Languages/Frameworks: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, EJS, Express
- Other Tools: Binance Websockets, NPM packages, ROBO 3T,
- Database: MongoDB (NoSQL)

2) Stock recommendation Bot [RPA]

A recommendation system based on Robotic Process Automation to suggest an ideal stock among NIFTY 50 for the investor to buy/sell at a given instant of time.

Developed a bot that would account for the parameters such as Open, High, Low, Close, Percentage Change and recommend the best stock to buy /sell at any given point of time all by a single click.

Tools used :

- Automation anywhere community edition
- Automation anywhere enterprise edition
- · Bot Lab

3)Wired Campus Network [Networking] : View the project on Github

Designed and **developed a suitable network system** for universities in developing countries. The aim was to create a network with **high security and low cost**. This project was developed to accelerate the growth of education in developing countries.

Tools used: Cisco Packet Tracer

4) Mill2Door [Web development]

Designed, developed, and managed the **frontend and the backend** of an **e-commerce site** using **WordPress** and **Woocommerce**. Integrated payment gateway via **Razorpay API** and **embedded Facebook Pixel** and **Google Analytics** to track user interactions and behavior to arrive at essential inferences.

Certificates and Achievements

- Internship offer from J.P Morgan Chase & Co after developing a solution for NGO-Uninhibited [view project] in 24 hours with total participants of 6000 students across India.
- Participated in Hackverse by NIT Surathkal [view certificate] and built Discourse-a
 debating app.
- Participated in Flipr Hackathon [view certificate] and built a Gmail clone [Frontend] in React.
- Participated in inter-college Hackathon [view certificate] by Department of CSE, DSCE and built a solution for parking problems faced by students in colleges.